Guide to the Bella Abzug papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Bella Abzug Papers,
1970-1976.
Abzug, Bella S., 1920-
ca. 554,100 items (185 v., 1116 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library. New York, NY.
4078361
History
Lawyer and Congresswoman from New York City's 19th and 20th Congressional Districts, 1971-1976. (Columbia LL.B.,1945)
Scope and Content
Congressional papers consisting of correspondence memoranda, speeches, reports, photographs and printed materials relating to her terms in Congress. The collection contains general correspondence and administrative files, as well as extensive subject files on a wide variety of topics with which Abzug was involved while in Congress. Also included are Legislative files, being the chronological files of background material for legislation considered on the House floor, and printed versions of legislation by Abzug and others. The Casework Files, relating to Abzug's advocacy on behalf of constituents involved in civil rights, housing, military, employment and related cases, are closed. Among the major correspondents are Carl Albert, Abraham D. Beame, Hugh L. Carey, Gerald R. Ford, Edward I. Koch, John V. Lindsay, Nelson A. Rockefeller, and Gloria Steinem. Materials added in 1981 include: draft transcripts of an oral history, appointment books, speeches and subject files (particularly on privacy and freedom of information) all interfiled in the collection and campaign materials press releases and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
The Papers are organized in 17 series and many subseries.
Series I: Catalogued Correspondents
Series II: Uncataloged Correspondence, Incoming
Series III: Uncataloged, outgoing
Series IV: Administrative Files
Series V: Subject Files
Series VI: Legislative Files
Series VII: Public Statements
Series VIII: Printed Materials
Series IX: Photographs
Series X: Records and Tapes
Series XI: Campaign memorabilia, Miscellaneous
Series XII: Oversize
Series XIII: Casework Files
Series XIV: 1981 Addition
Series XV: 1986 Addition
Series XVI: Audio Visual Material
Series XVII: Scrapbooks
Subjects
United States.--Congress.--House.; Koch, Ed, 1924-; Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet); Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and Government.; Oral histories; Photoprints; Politicians
Access Restrictions
Casework files and selected correspondence and administrative files closed; campaign materials, press releases and newspaper clippings from 1981 addition require Donor's permission to see.
The cataloged correspondence in Series I of this collection is located on-site.
The following boxes are located off-site: 1-1116. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1976 Papers Abzug, Bella Gift
1981 Addition Abzug, Bella Gift
- Series I: Catalogued Correspondents
  - (5 unnumbered Boxes)
  - Albert, Carl
  - Allende Beatriz
  - Allon, Yigal
  - Amory, Cleveland
  - Amram, David
  - Avedon, Richard
  - Beame, Abraham David
  - Benet, Laura Koch
  - Bentley, Eric R.
  - Berrigan, Philip
  - Bikel, Theodore
  - Black, Algernon David
  - Bloomgarden, Kermit
  - Bond, Julian
  - Brown, Edmund G., Jr.
  - Buckley, James L.
  - Buckley, William F., Jr.
  - Bundy, McGeorge
  - Burger, Warren E.
  - Burns, Arthur F.
  - Carey, Hugh L.
  - Carter, Jimmy
  - Celler, Emanuel
  - Chavez, Cesar E.
  - Chisholm, Shirley
  - Church, Frank
  - Clark, Ramsey
  - Clemens, Cyril
  - Cousins, Norman
  - Deutsch, Babette
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagan
  - Eaton, Cyrus
  - Ephron, Nora
  - Fonda, Jane
  - Ford, Elizabeth Bloomer (Mrs. Gerald R., Jr.)
  - Ford, Gerald R., Jr.
  - Fulbright, J. William
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth
  - Gardner, John W.
  - Goldwater, Barry M.
  - Grasso, Ella T.
  - Harriman, William Averell
  - Hatfield, Mark O.
  - Hayden, Tom
  - Hearst, Randolph A.
  - Hicks, Louise Day
  - Holtzman, Elizabeth
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio
  - Jackson, Henry M.
  - Javits, Jacob K.
  - Kelley, Clarence
  - Kempton, Murray
  - Kennedy, Edward M.
  - Kenneth
  - King, Billie Jean
  - Koch, Edward I.
  - Krupsak, Mary Anne
  - Kupferberg, Tuli
  - Lamont, Corliss
  - Lefkowitz, Louis J.
  - Lindsay, John Vliet
  - Luce, Clare Boothe
  - Luening, Otto
  - Lyons, Leonard
  - Macdonald, Dwight
  - MacLaine, Shirley
  - Maddox, Lester
  - Mansfield, Michael J.
  - McGovern, George S.
  - Mead, Margaret
  - Meany, George
  - Meeropol, Ellen (Mrs. Robert (Rosenberg])
  - Mills, Wilbur D.
  - Mitford, Jessica
  - Mondale, Walter F.
  - Moore, Paul, Jr.
  - Morris, Richard B.
  - Moses, Robert
  - Mott, Stewart'R.
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick
  - Muskie, Edmund S.
  - Myerson, Bess
  - Mygatt, Tracy D.
  - Nader, Ralph
  - O' Dwyer, Paul
  - O'Brien, Lawrence F.
  - O'Neill, Thomas P., Jr.
  - Papp, Joseph
  - Percy, Charles H.
  - Pogrebin, Letty Cottin
  - Proxmire, William
  - Ribicoff, Abraham
  - Richardson, Elliot L.
  - Rickover, Hyman George
  - Robbins, Jerome
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A.
  - Rockefeller, Winthrop
  - Rodino, Peter W., Jr.
  - Romney, George W.
  - Rukeyser, Muriel
  - Schary, Dore
  - Schiff, Dorothy
  - Schlafly, Phyllis
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr.
  - Scranton, William W.
  - Shriver, [Robert] Sargent, [Jr.]
  - Shriver, Eunice Kennedy (Mrs. Robert Sargent, Jr.)
  - Sparkman, John
  - Spock, Benjamin Steinem, Gloria
  - Sutton, Percy E.
  - Tcherepnin, Alexander
  - Thurmond, Strom
  - Trilling, Lionel
  - Udall, Morris K.
  - Wagner, Robert F.
  - Wallace, George C.
  - Wallace, Irving
  - Weidman, Jerome
  - Wilkins, Roy
  - Wilson, Malcolm
  - Witherspoon, Frances
  - Woodcock, Leonar
  - Young, Andrew
  - Zumwalt, Elmo Russell, Jr.
- Series II: Uncataloged Correspondence, Incoming
  - Subseries II.1: General
    This sequence contains primarily general letters received by Abzug's various offices. Many files also contain related items and copies of replies. Files of correspondence pertaining to specific issues have been placed in the Topics Files, q.v. One Box of Abzug's outgoing "Dear Colleague" letters have been kept with those she received, in this file, rather than in the Outgoing sequence of correspondence.
    - 1970 1971 January-August (Box 1)
    - 1971 September-December; 1971 letters referred (Box 2)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1975 January –December (Box 4)
    - 1975 "Funny Letters" (Box 5)
    - 1975-1976 Kaye Phillips File 1976 January--March (Box 5)
    - 1976 April--June (Box 6)
    - 1976 July-August (Box 7)
    - 1976 September-December (Box 8)
    - 1976 Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Subseries II.2: Abusive Mail
    - Abusive Mail, 1970-1976 (Box 9-10)
  - Subseries II.3: Condolences
    - Condolence cards--Outgoing, 1971-1976 (Box 11)
    - Incoming, 1975 (Box 11)
      (includes several catalogued items; catalogue cards in Box)
      - Subseries II.4: Congress, Members of
        - General, 1972, 1974-1976 (Box 12)
        - "Dear Colleague" Letters, 1971-1972 (Box 13)
        - "Dear Colleague II Letters, 1972, 1975, 1976 (Box 14)
        - "Dear Colleague" Letters by Abzug, 1971-1975 and n.d. (Box 15)
      - Subseries II.5: Congratulations
        - Congratulations, 1971-1976 and n.d. (Box 16)
      - Subseries II.6: Courtesy Letters
        - General letters of greeting and acknowledgement (Box 16)
        - 1970-1976 (Box 17-20)
      - Subseries II.7: Dead Letters
        - Dead Letters, 1971-1976 (Box 21)
      - Subseries II.8: Holiday and Birthday Greetings
        - Holiday and Birthday greetings (Box 22)
      - Subseries II.9: Literary Correspondence
        - Literary Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 23)
          (regarding literary works and activities by Abzug and others)
          - Subseries II.10: Recommendations
            - Recommendations, 1970--1976 (Box 24)
          - Subseries II.11: Requests
            - 1970-1974 (Box 25-27)
            - 1975
              - Agriculture Yearbook (Box 28)
              - Autographs (Box 28)
              - Bills (Box 28)
              - Biographies (Box 28)
              - Celebrity Auctions Messages (Box 28)
              - Photographs (Box 28)
              - Questionnaires Recipes (Box 28)
              - White House Tours (Box 28)
            - 1976
              - General (four Folders) (Box 29)
              - Agricultural publications (Box 29)
              - Autographs (Box 29)
              - Bills (Box 29)
              - Biographies (Box 29)
              - Celebrity Auctions (Box 29)
              - Directory of Services for the Elderly, 20th C.D. (Box 29)
              - Endorsements (Box 29)
              - Photographs (Box 29)
              - Questionnaires (Box 29)
          - Subseries II.12: Support
            - Support General, 1970-1974 (Box 30)
            - General, 1975-1976 (Box 31)
            - "Friends of BSA " 1976. (Box 31)
            - National Constituents of Bella Abzug, 1971 (Box 31)
            - National Constituents of Bella Abzug, 1971-1975 (Box 32)
          - Subseries II.13: Thanks and Commendations
            - Thanks and Commendations, 1970-1976 (Box 33-35)
          - Subseries II.14: Views, General
            - (letters of opinion on various subjects from constituents and others. See also specific Topics files.) (Box 33-35)
            - 1971-1976 (Box 36-39)
          - Subseries II.15: White House correspondence
            - White House correspondence (Box 40)
- Series III: Uncataloged, outgoing
  This series contains carbon copies of letters sent from Abzug's New York and Washington offices; the files of the two offices are kept separate. Due to inconsistencies and changes in filing systems, there are some overlapping points in the sequences.
  - Subseries III.1: New York Office
    - 1970 December--1972 May (Box 41)
    - 1972 June--December; 1972 A--Z (Box 42)
    - 1973 (Box 43)
    - 1973 A--Z (1981 Addition) (Box 43A)
    - 1974 (Box 44)
    - 1974 A--Z (1981 Addition) (Box 44A)
    - 1975 1-12; A--K (Box 45)
    - 1975 L--Z; 1976 1-12; 1976 A –Z (Box 45A)
  - Subseries III.2: Washington Office
    - 1971-1972 (Box 46-47)
    - Copies sent to New York office, 1971 1973--1974 (Box 48)
    - 1971-1972 A-Z (Box 49-52)
    - 1973--1976 A-Z (Box 53-62)
    - "Robos" (form letters signed by robot) 1974--1976 (1981 Addition) (Box 62A)
- Series IV: Administrative Files
  - Subseries IV.1: Personal
    - Awards and Honors (Box 63)
    - Biographies (Box 63)
    - Biographies--Correspondence I Biographies--Directories (Box 63)
    - Biographies--Oral History (draft transcripts, taped 1971-; not Columbia) (Box 63A)
    - Campaign, 1970 (Box 64)
      - Auto rental (Box 64)
      - Campaign song Canvassing (Box 64)
      - Chertov, Eva, 19th CD (Box 64)
      - Cozmnentary article (Box 64)
      - Correspondence (Box 64)
      - Election organization (Box 64)
      - Fair Campaign Practices Committee (Box 64)
      - Farber, Barry (Box 64)
      - Farbstein, Leonard (Box 64)
      - Issue Statements (Box 64)
      - Letters (Box 64)
      - Lobby, 18 March 1970 (Box 64)
      - Questionnaires (Box 64)
      - Reform designation (Box 64)
      - Shanker, reply to (Box 64)
      - Signature requirements (Box 64)
      - WOR spots (Box 64)
      - WOR (FCC case) (Box 64)
    - Campaign, 1972 (Box 64)
    - Campaign, 1976 and n.d. (SEE ALSO Restricted Files, 1981 Addition) (Box 64)
    - Organizations: (Box 65)
      - 1971-1976 (Box 65)
      - American Bar Association (Box 65)
      - National Constituents of Bella Abzug (Box 65)
  - Subseries IV.2: Office
    - Office--General: (Box 66)
      - Bugging incident, October 1972 (Box 66)
      - Constituent mailings (Box 66)
      - Equipment, supplies, expenses (Box 66)
      - Files (Box 66)
      - General Services Administration (Box 66)
      - Government Printing Office (Box 66)
      - Guest Book (Box 66)
      - Lower East Side Office (Box 66)
      - Mail Tallies, weekly (Box 66)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 66)
      - Newsletters (Box 66)
      - Office procedure manual (Box 66)
      - Questionnaires (sample) (Box 66)
      - Subscriptions (Box 66)
    - Address Lists: (Box 67)
      - Assembly Districts (Box 67)
      - Civic Organizations (Box 67)
      - Favorable voters (Box 67)
      - National Legislative Directory (Box 67)
      - Religious organizations and houses of worship (Box 67)
      - White House (Box 67)
      - Cards and notes (Box 67)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 Folders) (Box 67)
    - Memoranda, 1970--1976 and n.d., (4 Folders) (Box 68)
    - Notes, 1971-1972 and n.d. (Box 68)
    - Memoranda, 1973-75 [Confidential] (Box 69)
    - Staff: (Box 70)
      - Resumes, A-R (Box 70)
      - Resumes, S--Z (Box 72)
      - On Staff (Box 72)
      - Volunteers (Box 72)
    - Interns: (Box 73-75)
      - 1971-1977 (contains catalogued item, with card [Confidential] (Box 73-75)
      - Related material (Box 75)
      - Sample letters (Box 75)
      - University and school programs (Box 75)
  - Subseries IV.3: Public Activities
    - Sub-Subseries IV.3.1: Invitations
      - Occasionally included in these files are Abzug's itineraries, drafts of speeches and other related items. (Box 75)
      - 1970 Accepted and declined (Box 76)
      - 1971 Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 76)
      - Accepted: (Box 76)
      - General (Box 76)
      - Contacts-Florida
        - Florida (Box 76)
        - Illinois (Box 76)
        - Maryland (Box 76)
        - Missouri (Box 76)
        - North Carolina (Box 76)
        - Texas (Box 76)
        - Washington (Box 76)
        - Wisconsin (Box 76)
        - England (Box 76)
        - Students (Box 76)
    - 1971 Accepted (Box 77)
    - 1971 Declined (Box 78)
    - 1971 Declined (by state): (Box 79)
      - -Arizona (Box 79)
      - -Arkansas (Box 79)
      - -California (Box 79)
      - -Connecticut Colorado (Box 79)
      - -District of ..Columbia (2) (Box 79)
      - -Florida Georgia Idaho (Box 79)
      - -Indiana (Box 79)
      - -Illinois (Box 79)
      - K--W (Box 80)
    - Foreign (Box 80)
    - 1972 Accepted--January-August (Box 81)
    - 1972 Accepted--September-December By state/Country A-Z (Box 82)
    - 1972 Declined--January-December (Box 83)
    - 1972 Declined--By State, A--I (Box 84)
    - 1972 Declined--By state, K--Y (Box 85)
    - 1973 Accepted--January--December (Box 86)
    - 1973 Accepted--By state: (Box 87)
      - -California. (Box 87)
      - -Delaware (Box 87)
      - -District of Columbia Florida. (Box 87)
      - -Kentucky (Box 87)
      - -Louisiana (Box 87)
      - -New York (Box 87)
      - -Ohio (Box 87)
      - -Pennsylvania (Box 87)
      - -Texas (Box 87)
    - 1973 Declined (Box 88-89)
    - 1974 Accepted (Box 90-91)
    - Accepted, By state (Box 91)
      - -Colorado (Box 91)
      - -Connecticut (Box 91)
      - -Maryland (Box 91)
      - -Massachusetts (Box 91)
      - -Nebraska (Box 91)
      - -New Jersey (Box 91)
      - -New York (Box 91)
      - -West Virginia (Box 91)
      - -Wisconsin (Box 91)
      - -State contacts (Box 91)
      - -St. Martens (Box 91)
    - 1974 Declined (Box 92-95)
    - 1975 Declined (Box 96-98)
    - 1975 Declined By state, Alabama-Wisconsin, and out-of-country (Box 99)
    - 1975 Response not indicated (Box 100)
    - 1976 Accepted (Box 101)
    - 1976 Declined (Box 102-104)
    - 1976 Response not indicated (Box 105-106)
    - Miscellaneous: Engagements, NY--declined (Box 107)
    - Engagements, NY--past (Box 107)
    - Programs and seating arrangements (Box 107)
    - Speakers' Bureaus
      - Sub-Subseries IV.3.2 Schedules
        - Including some related correspondence, memoranda, and printed items (Box 107)
        - 1971-1973 (Box 108)
        - 1974-1975 No date or no year "Drop-ins" (Box 109)
        - Foreign Contacts (D.C. meetings with) (Box 109)
        - Requests for Appointments (Box 109)
        - Appointment books, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1975 (Box 109A)
    - Subseries IV.4: Public Relations
      - Sub-Subseries IV.4.1: Literary
        - Abzug, Bella S., Bella!.. Manuscript (Box 110)
        - Publicity and Sales Reception (Box 110)
        - Reprint (Box 110)
        - Reviews (Box 110)
        - Abzug, Bella S., The Candidate--Review (Box 110)
        - Abzug, Bella S., First Generation Americans (Box 110)
        - Abzug, Bella S., Massachusetts Review article 1971 (Box 110)
        - miscellaneous (Box 110)
        - Agent (Box 110)
        - Contracts and Statements (Box 110)
        - Works about Abzug (Box 110)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 110)
        - Mass Mailings, 1974 (Box 111)
      - Sub-Subseries IV.4.2: Press
        - Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 111)
        - Clippings (SEE Also: Bound volumes, Restricted) (Box 111)
        - Political Cartoons (Box 111)
        - Radio (Box 111)
        - Speeches, Statements and Releases--Drafts, 1973 Note: Most copies of speeches and statements, where they exist, remain with the files where they were originally kept, notably the Invitations and Congressional testimony files and also in the files relating to specific subjects (Box 111)
        - Television--1970-1976 (Box 111)
        - Miscellaneous--"King of Capitol Hill," 1975 (Box 111)
        - Miscellaneous--Press Releases by others (Box 111)
      - Sub-Subseries IV.4.3: 20th C.D. Community Conference
        - General (Box 112)
        - Financial (Box 112)
        - lists (Box 112)
        - 1973
          - General (Box 112)
          - Correspondence (Box 112)
          - Poll (Box 112)
          - Cash Book (Box 112)
          - Consumer Panel (Box 112)
          - Education Panel (Box 112)
          - Elderly Panel (Box 112)
          - Environment Panel (Box 112)
          - Health Panel (Box 112)
          - Housing Panel (Box 112)
          - Jobs Panel (Box 112)
          - Jobs and Women Panel (Box 112)
        - 1974 (Box 113)
          - General (Box 113)
          - Correspondence (Box 113)
          - Financial Lists (Box 113)
          - Panel Lists (Box 113)
          - Press (Box 113)
          - Registration Materials (Box 113)
          - Energy Panel (Box 113)
          - Food Panel (Box 113)
          - Health Pane1 (Box 113)
          - Housing Panel (Box 113)
          - Transportation Pane1 (Box 113)
          - Related Material (Box 113)
        - 1975 (Box 114)
          - General (Box 114)
          - Correspondence (Box 114)
          - Financial (Box 114)
          - Lists (Sponsors and Donors) (Box 114)
          - Panelists (Box 114)
          - Plenary Session Speakers (Box 114)
          - Press (Box 114)
          - Registration Materials (Box 114)
          - Federal Role in the Arts Panel (Box 114)
          - Public Ownership Pane1 (Box 114)
          - Right to a Job Panel (Box 114)
          - Social Security Panel (Box 114)
          - Related Materials (Box 114)
    - Subseries IV.5: Essay Contest
      - 1973 Correspondence and Related Items Entries (Box 115)
      - 1974 Correspondence and Related Items Entries, (2 Folders) (Box 115)
    - Subseries IV.6: Litigation
      - (Material relating primarily to legal cases involving Abzug) (Box 116)
      - -General Correspondence (Box 116)
      - -Miscellaneous Cases (Box 116)
      - -Related Printed Items (Box 116)
      - 1971 (Box 116)
      - 1972 Capitol Steps/Mayday Cases (Box 116)
      - 1972 Mink vs. E.P.A. (Box 116)
      - 1971 U.S. vs. Washington Post (Box 116)
      - 1971 U.S. Congress vs. Nixon (Box 116)
      - 1972 Levy vs. Abzug (Box 117)
      - 1972- (Box 117)
      - 1974 Sharrow vs. Abzug et al.. (Box 117)
      - 1973 Abzug vs. Schlesinger (Box 117)
      - 1973 Miller vs. Staats (Box 117)
      - 1974 Abzug vs. Saxbe (Box 117)
      - 1974 Dellums/Abzug vs. Powell (Capitol Steps Case) (Box 117)
      - 1974 National Lawyers Guild--1972 Election Case (Box 117)
      - 1974 San Clemente Case (Stokes vs. G. S.A.) (Box 117)
      - 1974 U.S. vs. Nixon (tapes) (Box 117)
      - 1976 Abzug vs. Richardson (Box 117)
- Series V: Subject Files
  - Subseries V.1: Aged
    - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 118)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 119)
    - Abzug:
      - Congressional Record statements (Box 119)
      - Directory of Services for the Elderly in the 20th Congressional District (printed copy with related correspondence and bills) (Box 119)
      - Legislation Sponsored by Abzug--Bills and related material (Box 119)
      - Notes and Memoranda (Box 119)
      - Press Releases (Box 119)
      - Abzug: (Box 120)
      - Public Activities –miscellaneous (Box 120)
      - Speeches, Testimony and Floor Remarks (Box 120)
    - Health:
      - General (Box 120)
      - Medicare (SEE ALSO: Health--Medicare/Medicaid) (Box 120)
      - Nutrition (Box 120)
    - Housing Jewish Legislation--General (Box 120)
    - Housing Jewish Legislation--Older Americans Act of 1965 with amendments (Box 120)
    - New York City: (Box 121)
    - General Centers (Box 121)
    - New York City Office for the Aging, 1969-1973 (Box 121)
    - New York City Office for the Aging, 1974-1976 (Box 122)
    - New York City offices and departments, miscellaneous (Box 122)
    - Organizations, miscellaneous (Box 122)
    - Organizations--Washington Heights/Inwood Council (Box 122)
    - Programs, miscellaneous (Box 122)
    - Programs--Community Concern for Senior Citizens; New York City Community College (Box 122)
    - Programs--PATH (Employment) (Box 122)
    - New York State--General (Box 123)
    - New York State Office for the Aging (Box 123)
    - Nursing Homes:
      - General (Box 123)
      - Correspondence (Box 123)
      - American Jewish Congress (Box 123)
      - Fire Safety Hearings, U.S. House of Representatives (Box 123)
      - Legislation, General (Box 124)
      - Legislation Sponsored by Abzug (Box 124)
      - Memoranda, Notes, Drafts of Statements and Correspondence (Box 124)
      - New York City--General
        - Isabella Nursing Home (Box 124)
      - New York State (Box 124)
      - U. S. Government Standards and Programs (Box 124)
      - U.S. Senate Special Committee on Aging (Box 124)
      - Printed--Miscellaneous publications (Box 124)
      - Printed--Clippings and miscellaneous items (Box 124)
    - Organizations--General (Box 125)
      - Gray Panthers (Box 125)
      - National Council on the Aging (Box 125)
      - Seniors for Adequate Social Security (SASS) (Box 125)
      - Wildcat (Handyman services) (Box 125)
    - Pensions and Income (Box 125)
    - Social Security (Box 125)
    - Transportation:
      - Correspondence (Box 125)
      - Legislation (Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964) (Box 125)
      - Memoranda, Notes and Releases (Box 125)
      - New York City (Box 125)
      - New York State (Box 126)
      - Reports and Studies (Box 126)
      - U.S. Department of Transportation (Box 126)
      - U.S. Government Hearings and Testimony (Box 126)
    - U.S. Government:
      - Hearings and Reports (Box 126)
      - Programs and Standards (Box 126)
    - U.S. Senate Special Committee on Aging (Box 126)
    - Printed--Reports, Publications and Clippings (Box 126)
  - Subseries V.2: Animals
    - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 127)
    - Cats and Dogs (Box 127)
    - Experimentation (Box 127)
    - Legislation (Box 127)
    - Organizations (Box 127)
    - Traps (Box 127)
    - Whales (Box 127)
    - Wolves (Box 127)
  - Subseries V.3: Arts, Letters and Humanities
    - Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 128)
    - Abzug--Legislation on arts and humanities (Box 129)
    - Film (Box 129)
    - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (Box 129)
    - New York City:
      - General (Box 129)
      - Artists' Day (Box 129)
      - Bronx Council on the Arts (Box 129)
      - Bronx--miscellaneous (Box 129)
      - Community Environments (Box 129)
      - Morris-Jumel Mansion (Box 129)